proxyduck.co 2017-11-05

# Privacy | Neustar

**Highlights of the Neustar Privacy Policy**

_Updated: October 10, 2017_

Neustar uses Personal Information to support data-driven decision-making and deliver personalized content without sacrificing personal privacy. These “Highlights” summarize Neustar’s privacy practices. You can learn more by clicking on the links below, and by reviewing the Neustar Privacy Policy and Privacy Principles

### Our Commitment – Privacy by Design

We follow the Neustar Privacy Principles, including the principle of Privacy by Design, to design, build, and deliver products and services that respect your privacy.

### Personal Information Collection, Use, and Disclosure

We collect Personal Information from you directly and from businesses that use our products and services. We use registration data, including Personal Information, supplied by our online Match Partners to set AdAdvisor Cookies and/or Aggregate Knowledge Cookies, which do not contain or convey Personal Information. Finally, we collect and use Personal Information and other demographic data from a variety of sources such as telephone directories, the US Postal Service, the Census Bureau, and from other third parties. We do not use Sensitive Personal Information without your permission.

Read our full Privacy Policy or click on the links below to learn more about the Personal Information we collect and how we use it:

  * Data Collected On Our Websites
  * Data Collected and Used to Provide Neustar Products and Services
  * Other Use and Disclosure of Personal Information

### Cookies, Advertising IDs and Other Technologies

Neustar may use cookies, web beacons, pixel tags, javascript, HTML5 local storage, or similar technologies, along with other information described in our Privacy Policy to enhance and personalize your experience on our sites and to manage and enable preferences, transactions and related uses of Neustar services and information. In addition, we use Mobile Advertising IDs, also known as IDFA or IFA, in connection with PlatformOneSM and other marketing services. Third parties with whom we partner may use cookies, web beacons, pixel tags, javascript, HTML5 local storage, or Flash LSOs to help us understand how visitors interact with our website or to deliver content, such as videos, or to personalize ads you see online based on your visits to our website.

Read our full Privacy Policy or click on the links below to learn more about the technologies we use:

  * Website Cookies
  * Analytics and Segmentation Cookies
  * Mobile Advertising IDs

### Transparency and Choice; Opt-Out

##### Cookies

  * You can opt out of the use of AdAdvisor Cookies and AK Cookies for Neustar Marketing Services on the Opt-Out page of our website.
  * You can also opt out of the use of AdAdvisor Cookies and AK Cookies for Neustar Marketing Services by using the Digital Advertising Alliance (DAA) tool on the <http://www.aboutads.info/choices/> page.
  * You can opt out of interest-based advertising served by companies that participate in the Digital Advertising Alliance's Consumer Choice tool by visiting <http://aboutads.info/choices>.

##### Mobile Advertising IDs

  * Apple’s iOS IDFA can be reset by the user at any time. Users can opt out of all remarketing by enabling a device setting called "Limit Ad Tracking" (LAT), which restricts advertisers from using the IDFA for behavioral advertising. You can learn how to limit ad tracking on your iOS device or to reset your IDFA here: [IDFA Opt-Out](http://support.apple.com/kb/HT4228).
  * Similar to IDFA for Apple devices, Android devices pass Google Advertising ID, which provides the same type of device-specific, unique, resettable ID for advertising as Apple IDFA or IFA. You can learn more about how identifiers on mobile are used for advertising and receive instruction for how to opt out of mobile advertising on the [Google Privacy & Terms](http://www.google.com/policies/technologies/ads/) webpage.

Please note that opting out does not mean you will block online advertising altogether or see fewer ads. It simply means that the ads that you see will not be personalized for you. Ads may be served because they relate to the website you are visiting or to your current search, or they may just be randomly placed.

Your choice to opt out from the use of AK and AdAdvisor cookies will not affect ads placed by any other organization.

We comply with opt-out requests by placing an “opt-out cookie” on your computer or device. Consequently, if you clear your cookies on that computer or device, we will not be able to read our “opt-out cookie” and will resume collecting information from that computer or device for purposes of retargeting. Similarly, an opt-out request will not be effective on other browsers, computers, or devices you may use if you have not opted out while using that browser, computer, or device.

### Accountability

Neustar is a member of the [Network Advertising Initiative](https://www.networkadvertising.org/) (“NAI”) and the [Digital Advertising Alliance](http://www.aboutads.info/) (“DAA”) and adheres to each organization’s Codes and Principles. You can also learn more about online advertising in general on the [NAI](https://www.networkadvertising.org/) website, which provides background information on participating companies and permits you to opt-out of receiving tailored online advertising from some or all of its members. For information about the DAA Self-Regulatory Program for Online Behavioral Advertising and to learn more about the Ad Choices icon, visit <http://www.aboutads.info/> and <http://youradchoices.com/>.

Aggregate Knowledge adheres to the European Interactive Digital Advertising Alliance’s (“EDAA”) principles. You may learn more about our participation in the EDAA’s program and online behavioral advertising at [www.youronlinechoices.eu](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/).

### EU-U.S. Privacy Shield and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield

Neustar and its subsidiaries (i.e., .CO Internet S.A.S., Neustar Information Services, Inc., Aggregate Knowledge, Inc., and MarketShare Holdings, Inc., together, “Neustar”) participate in and have certified their compliance with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework and the Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework. We are committed to subjecting all personal data received from European Union (EU) member countries and Switzerland, respectively, in reliance on each Privacy Shield Framework, to the Framework’s applicable Principles. To learn more about the Privacy Shield Frameworks, and to view our certification, visit the U.S. Department of Commerce’s Privacy Shield List here: [https://www.privacyshield.gov](https://www.privacyshield.gov/).

Neustar is responsible for the processing of personal data it receives, under each Privacy Shield Framework, and subsequently transfers to a third party acting as an agent on its behalf. Neustar complies with the Privacy Shield Principles for all onward transfers of personal data from the EU and Switzerland, including the onward transfer liability provisions.

With respect to personal data received or transferred pursuant to the Privacy Shield Frameworks, Neustar is subject to the regulatory enforcement powers of the U.S. Federal Trade Commission. In certain situations, we may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.

If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S.-based third party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) at <https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request>.

Under certain conditions, more fully described on the [Privacy Shield](https://www.privacyshield.gov/article?id=How-to-Submit-a-Complaint) website here, you may be entitled to invoke binding arbitration when other dispute resolution procedures have been exhausted.

European residents may also opt-out of the use of AK Cookies for online advertising at: [www.youronlinechoices.eu](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/)

### TRUSTe Certification

Neustar, Inc. has received TRUSTe's Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy statement and our practices have been reviewed for compliance with the TRUSTe program viewable on the validation page available by clicking the TRUSTe seal. If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact TRUSTe at <https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request>.

The TRUSTe program covers only information that is collected through this Web site, and the, IP Intelligence, PlatformOne, and UltraDNS platforms.

### The Fine Print

Click here to read our full Privacy Policy and to learn more about our approach to children’s privacy, data security, disclosures required by law or for other purposes, and your privacy rights under California law.

Our privacy practices and policies may be updated from time to time. We will post a notice regarding material changes on our web site.

### Questions? Comments?

Send us an email at: [privacy@neustar.biz](mailto:privacy@neustar.biz)
